Guide to the Park City Mountain Resort audio-visual collection 1961-2002
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Extreme Winter, 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 108)
  This video is a Warren Miller production and is a screening copy only. It highlights the extreme side of skiing with cliff jumping, snowboarding, deep powder skiing, and mogul skiing. The world's best freestyle riders travel with Warren Miller to Grand Targee, Blackcomb British Columbia, Breckenridge Colorado, to Vermont for the freestyle legends competition, the Colorado Rockies, to an untracked and unnamed mountain in Antarctica, Mammoth, France and to Moscow to find the greatest thrills on skis and snowboards. The U.S. Men's Ski Team and the junior race team are also highlighted in this production.
- Corporate ski challenge, 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 109)
  The corporate ski challenge is based on the idea of leaving the stresses of a corporate lifestyle behind and heading to the mountains to get some fresh air and to have fun. Each major corporation races against another in a relay race where the competitors play tug-a-war on skis and ski the course with only one ski. The race takes place at the Alpine Meadows ski area and is followed by live music and dancing.
- "The World According To Spyder", "Dress To Thrill", "Push It to the Limit", 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 110)
  "The World According To Spyder" and "Dress To Thrill" are advertisements for Spyder ski gear featuring the United States Ski Team, Team Michelob Light/ Spyder, Team Memorex/ Spyder, Scott Kauf, Nelson Carmichael, Robert Aguirre, Roger Aguirre, Scott Kennett, Torjus Berge, Ove Nygren, Niklas Lindqvist, Joel Gaspoz, Christian Orlainsky, Scott Rawles, Hansi Standteiner, Kent Kreitler, Bart Tuttle, Joe Vranka, Ski Club Vail Kyds, Jeff Temple, David Jacobs, Kevin Kaneda, Tom Arnstein, Rianne Aguirre, and Katherine Knowlton.
  "Push It to the Limit" promotes extreme sports. It features extreme snow skiing, barefoot water skiing, motorcycling, skate boarding, climbing and kayaking.
- Ski Demo, 1990; Audiocassette (Cassette 111)
  This tape contains an advertisement for three interconnected mountains on the east coast: Killington, Smugglers Notch, and Piko. The advertisement highlights the snow conditions, ticket prices and short lift lines.
- Park City Ski Area advertisements, 1990; Audiocassette (Cassette 112)
  This tape contains two thirty-second advertisements for Park City Ski Area.
  The first advertises Park City as a leading ski area due to it's large lift capacity, vast terrain, and low ticket prices.
  The second advertises the resident coupon book offered by Park City Ski Area as well as other cheap ticket options for residents.
- Park City Ski Area advertisements revised, 1990; Audiocassette (Cassette 113)
  This tape contains three thirty-second advertisements for Park City Ski Area. All three advertise money saving options on season passes and day tickets.
- Television news coverage, 1990 November 05-1991 April 30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 114)
  11/5 KSL Noon "Park City is opening tomorrow"
  6 pm "Ski resorts will begin opening"
  KUTV 6 pm "Snow storm makes ski resorts happy"
  11/6 KSL 6:30 pm "Park City will open some lifts today"
  KUTV 10 pm "Park City will open some lifts today"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Park City will open some lifts today"
  11/19 KSL 10 pm "America's Cup at Park City"
  11/20 KTVX 5:30 pm "Lonnie Ivey disabled skier"
  10 pm "Cutting edge series part one"
  11/21 KUTV 5 pm "Park City prepares for big thanksgiving"
  6 pm "snow making machines at Park City"
  KTVX 10 pm "Cutting edge series part two"
  11/22 KTVX 5:30 pm "Phil and Steve Maher / America's Cup"
  11/23 KSL 10 pm "America's Cup"
  KUTV 10 pm "America's Cup"
  KTVX 10 pm "America's Cup"
  11/24 KUTV 6 pm "America's Cup"
  KTVX 5 pm "America's Cup"
  10 pm "America's Cup"
  10 pm "Closing ftg. Of the America's Cup"
  11/25 KSL 5:30 pm "America's Cup"
  Sports beat "America's Cup"
  KUTV 5:30 pm "America's Cup"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "America's Cup"
  11/24 KSL 10 pm "Pet Olympics"
  11/25 KUTV 10 pm "Park City veteran honored"
  No December
  1/3/91 KUTV 6 pm "Liquor license at summit house and Snow Hut"
  1/7/91 KTVX 10 pm "U of U Air-med"
  1/9 KSL 6 pm "Handicapped skiers"
  1/15 KUTV 6 pm "IOC visits Park City"
  KTVX 5:30 "War and the Senators Cup"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "IOC visits"
  1/28 KUTV 6 pm "NBS"
  1/30 KSL 10 pm "NBS"
  1/31 KTVX 5:30 pm "NBS"
  2/17 KUTV 5:30 pm "NBS"
  2/23 KSL 6 pm "Jans handicapped ski race"
  KTVX 5 pm "Jans handicapped ski race"
  2/27 KSL 6 pm "NCAA"
  KUTV 10 pm "NCAA"
  KTVX 10 pm "NCAA"
  3/01 KSL 10 pm "NCAA"
  3/03 KSL Sports beat "NCAA"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "High Winds"
  3/04 KUTV 5 pm "High Winds"
  3/05 KUTV Noon "Jimmie Heuga Ski Express"
  3/09 KTVX 5 pm "Handicapped skiing"
  3/19 KTVX 5:30pm "Huntsman Games"
  3/23 KUTV 10 pm "Jimmie Heuga MS Ski Express"
  3/29 KTVX 5:30 pm "Spring Skiing"
  4/22 KTVX 5:30 pm "Writers Fam tour"
  4/05 KTVX 5:30 pm "Military appreciation day"
  4/24 KUTV 6 pm "Development project"
  KUTV 10 pm "Development project"
  KTVX 10 pm "Development project"
  4/30 KTVX 10 pm "Delicate Balance part one"
- Ski demo, 1990-1991; Audiocassette (Cassette 115)
  This tape contains four separate advertisements. The first one is for the Killington ski area and advertises the improved technology of their snow making equipment, the great terrain, short lift lines, and low-ticket prices. The second one is for Smugglers Notch in Vermont and advertises the great terrain, the short lift lines, and low ticket and season pass prices. The third is for Ski Blue and advertises the great powder and tree runs as well as low season pass prices. The fourth advertisement is for the Piko ski area and is in the format of a radio show. It highlights the high-speed quad lifts, the high elevation of their peaks, their long runs, and their plentiful expert terrain.
- Steamboat Weather Summit, 1991 January 14-18; VHS videocassette (Cassette 116)
  This video contains footage from a ski event held at Steamboat Colorado. The event includes driving four-wheel-drive vehicles on a snow and ice course followed by tips for driving in icy conditions, and a southwestern ski race. The ski race is not a typical race but more of a relay race on snow. The relay race includes tasks such as skiing through a patch of heavy brush, then through gates and putting a saddle on a horse with skis still on.
- Ski Tips, 1991 February 13; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 117)
  This video contains an episode from the British television show Ski Tips featuring Park City Ski Area. The show starts out with a brief history of Salt Lake City, and an interview with Merrile Osmond. It then turns to Park City to highlight the America's Opening races and the street dance, live music, and the Wasatch Brewery. After giving a brief history of Park City, the hosts hit the slopes and give some tips on carving turns. They tour Park City Ski Area and explain how the hostess program operates. They show the costs of traveling to Utah including airfare, car and equipment rentals, and accommodations.
- Ski host, 1991 March 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 118)
  This video contains a news report on a skier who was charged with trespassing because he was giving ski lesson at Park City Ski Area but was not an employee of the ski area. He entered a plea of Not Guilty due to his claims of receiving nothing in return for giving people a few ski tips.
- Park City Ski Area advertisement, 1991 September; Audiocassette (Cassette 119)
  This tape contains a thirty-second advertisement for Park City Ski Area's discounted season pass rates.
- "Introduction to the Gift of Skiing" commercials, October 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 120)
  This video contains two commercials and a promotional video:
  The first commercial is a thirty-second commercial titled "Ski it to believe it" which encourages people to try skiing. The second commercial is sixty-seconds also encouraging people to learn to ski.
  The promotional video "Getting Started" encourages people to learn to ski through correcting the preconceived notions that it is too cold or too difficult or too expensive. It provides information on renting equipment, accommodations, ski club programs, ticket prices, clothing requirements, and slope ratings and introduces skiing as a family sport and as a sport for people of all ages. 22 minutes.
- Park City media, 1991 November 13; Betacam videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 121)
  This video contains aerial footage of Park City Ski Area and Park City's mine shafts as well as footage of the high speed quad lifts, clips from the Pro Cup Ski races, the weekend events from America's Opening World Cup races, and the main street in Park City, Utah.
- Park City World Cup farewell, 1991 November 24; VHS videocassette (Cassette 122)
  This video summarizes the 1991 America's Opening World Cup at Park City Ski Area. It contains clips from the 1991 World Cup races, the street dance and live music in Park City, junior races and the award ceremonies.
- America's Opening World Cup: men's slalom, 1991 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 123)
  This video contains highlights from the first run of the men's slalom event and a full live coverage of the second run. It also includes a VISA sponsored skier profile of Matt Grosjean and an interview with Alberto Tomba.
  The second portion of the Iron Man triathlon is attached at the end of this tape.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1991 November 24; Betacam videocassette, U-matic videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 124)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City Ski Area over Thanksgiving weekend. It highlights the times, dates, events and ticket information.
- Park City Ski Area national and local advertisement, 1991 December 10; VHS videocassette, Betacam videocassette, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 125-126)
  This video contains a thirty-second national and a thirty-second local advertisement for Park City Ski Area. It advertises Park City as the largest ski area in Utah with the fastest and greatest number of chair lifts and the most variation in terrain.
- America's Opening World Cup, 1991 December 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 127)
  This video contains footage of the ski racers preparing for races, the men's giant slalom and the first run of the men's slalom race.
- America's Opening World Cup sponsorship, 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 128)
  This video captures the excitement and enthusiasm of the America's Opening World Cup event. It features clips from the 1991 races, the live music at the Park City street dance, the fireworks, and the flag parade. It portrays the weekend as a celebration of ski racing and a time for all to share their love for skiing. After these clips, the sponsors explain the benefits of supporting the team. The sponsors include VISA, Subaru, Park City Ski Area, and Coca Cola. 6:40
- America's Opening original billboard cereal boxes, 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 129)
  This video contains a still picture of a list of all of the sponsors for the America's Opening World Cup race on the original billboard.
- Park City Legends, 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 130)
  "Filmed at Park City using all local talent. Marvel At the skill and endurance of Park City's nationally ranked young freestylers as they ski the grueling bumps. Be amazed as Bob Theobald soars over an incredible one-hundred-and-ten foot cliff. Learn what to do and see in all of Park City's seasons in the video visitors guide at the end of the film." Featured skiers include Stein Eriksen, Bob Theobald, Bob Salerno, Bobbie Burns, Beau Brinkerhoff, Mick Berry, Mark Verrone, Craig Rodman, Dave Berry, and David Dunn.
- A Fanfare To U.S. Skiing: Commitment, 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 131)
  Promotional video for the U.S. Ski Team and Subaru's sponsorship of them. It reviews the history of Subaru's sponsorship of the team and the history and future of U.S. Ski racing.
- Television news coverage, 1991 October 03-1992 April 03; VHS videocassette (Cassette 132)
  10/03 KUTV 10 pm "Predictions and making snow"
  10/28 KSL 6 pm
  KUTV Noon
  11/3 KTVX 10 pm "Predictions of banner year"
  11/11 KUTV 5 pm "Preparing for the World Cup"
  11/18 KUTV 11 pm "Much needed snow comes"
  11/21 KSL 9 pm
  KUTV 6 pm "Jeremy Nobis profile"
  11/22 KUTV 6 pm "America's Cup opening, concert prep"
  KTVX 5:30 "Prize money"
  KTVX 10 pm "Prize money and concert"
  11/23 KSL 6 pm "America's Cup results"
  KUTV 6 pm "Travel and tourism and results"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Race results"
  KTVX 10 pm "Handling major events and results"
  11/24 KSL 5:30 pm "Results"
  KUTV 10 pm "Concert closing"
  KUTV Sports Den "Results"
  KTVX 10 pm "Results and highlights"
  11/25 KTVX 10 pm "Lifts open"
  11/30 KTVX Images "Injuries"
  12/3 KTVX 5:30 pm "Out of state skiers, marketing"
  12/20 KTVX 5:30 pm "Ski Team profile - Kristi Terzian"
  12/26 KTVX Home Show "Ski Fitness"
  12/27 KTVX 5:30 "Escaping the inversion"
  1/2/92 KTVX 5:30 "Lift Operator profile"
  KTVX 10 pm "Senior citizen instructor"
  1/07 KTVX 10 pm "Utah Winter Games"
  1/08 KTVX 10 pm
  1/09 KTVX 10 pm
  1/11 KSL 6 pm "Ski survey"
  1/17 KTVX 5:30 pm "Profile of junior ski team"
  1/18 KTVX 5 pm "Senators Cup / Protests"
  1/27 KTVX 10 pm "Ski clinic for women"
  2/11 KTVX 10 pm "Nemeth skiing at Park City and night skiing at Park City Ski Resort"
  2/12 KSL 6:30 pm "Live from Park City: Freestyle skiing"
  2/13 KSL Focus "Handicapped Assoc. programs"
  2/16 KTVX 5:30 pm "New snow storms"
  2/17 KTVX 5:30 pm "Nobis recovering"
  2/20 KSL 6:30 pm "Live from ice rink: Utah Olympic team watches Albertville"
  2/22 KSL 5:30 pm "Jans Handicap Challenge and Snow sculpture"
  KTVX 5 pm
  KTVX Images Instructions for Olympic hopefuls"
  2/24 KTVX 10 pm "Jans Handicap Challenge"
  3/07 KTVX Images "Kids with cancer ski"
  3/16 KTVX 5:30 pm "Ski testing"
  3/17 KUTV 6 pm "New snow falls"
  3/21 KTVX 5 pm "Telemark championships"
  KTVX Images "Disabled / Huntsman Cup"
  KTVX 10 pm "Fundraiser for Nobis"
  KTVX 10 pm "Telemark competition"
  KTVX 10 pm (video close)
  3/28 KTVX Images
  4/03 KUTV 10 pm "Skaters perform"
- Mount Beagle, 1991; Audiocassette (Cassette 133)
  This tape contains an advertisement for Park City Ski Area. It advertises Park City's high-speed lifts, short lift lines, great terrain, dependable snow conditions, and low-ticket prices by comparing Park City Ski Area to a fictional ski area called Mount Beagle.
- Etc. Etc. - Utah and Park City special, 1992 February 06; VHS videocassette (Cassette 134)
  Etc. was a television series on the Travel Channel. This episode highlights Park City Ski Area in Utah. The show starts out with a special on the Utah ski patrol teams. They explain how they keep the slopes safe from avalanche danger and give some backcountry safety ski tips.
  The episode then travels to Albuquerque, New Mexico to spotlight mechanics who restore Chevrolets and to Massillon, Mexico for great fishing tips. Next they spotlight Washington State for their delicious apples, Bahamas for the intense tourism attraction, and then back to Park City for a brief history review. They also spotlight the relationship between Park City Ski Area and the U.S. Ski Team.
- Etc. Etc. - Utah skiing, 1992 February 07; VHS videocassette (Cassette 135)
  Etc. was a television series on the Travel Channel. This episode highlights the Deer Valley and Snowbird ski resorts. They show how Utah ski resorts help to protect the environment during the ski season as well as the off-season.
  The episode also spotlights unknown Mexico vacation destinations, learning to fly, and Eco tourism on the Bahamas peninsula.
- Etc. Etc. - Utah skiing, 1992 February 07; VHS videocassette (Cassette 136)
  Etc. Etc. was a television series on the Travel Channel. This episode gives a brief history of Park City's silver mining boom and why it became a bust. It introduces snowboarding as a new and exciting sport and spotlights a mountain that was built in Keystone Colorado.
  They also travel to Australia to introduce a man who captures the land down under unlike any other man can, to North Carolina for the history of the Grove Park Inn, and to the Bahamas to introduce the family islands.
- Park City marketing department, 1992 March 04; 1/4-inch tape data cartridge (Cartridge 137)
  No description is provided because 1/4-inch tape data cartridges could not be played at our facility at the time this collection was processed. However, our capabilities are constantly changing. Please contact a multimedia archivist about the current possibility of viewing this material.
  3 cartridges
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1992 November 02; VHS videocassette, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 138)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup even held at Park City Ski Area over the Thanksgiving weekend of 1992. It highlights times, dates, event schedule information and ticket information.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, event video, closing video, 1992 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 139)
  This video contains three segments:
  The first is the same advertisement for the America's Opening World cup as cassette 138.
  The second is an event video of the America's Opening World Cup. In this segment, the Giant Slalom and Slalom courses are defined by the amount of time spent in each course and by the number of gates. It also gives a brief history of various U.S. Ski Team members.
  The third segment is a closing video of the America's Opening World Cup. It shows the top three athletes in the racecourse and then receiving their awards.
- America's Opening event video, 1992 November; U-matic videocassette, VHS videocasstte (Cassette 140)
  This video contains the same footage as the second segment of cassette 139 along with some Olympic footage and a few interviews with women from the U.S. Ski Team who discuss what they get out of skiing.
  4 cassettes
- America's Opening World Cup footage, 1992 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 141)
  This video contains footage from the 1992 World Cup women's giant slalom and slalom races.
- America's Opening World Cup closing video, 1992 November; VHS videocassette, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 142)
  This video summarizes the America's Opening World Cup event. It also highlights the awards ceremony by showing the top three athletes racing and then receiving their awards.
- Adventures on Jupiter, 1992 October 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 143)
  This video features extreme skiing at Park City Ski Area. It starts out with a geographical description of Jupiter Peak and Jupiter Bowl. These areas are then described by various extreme skiers while the footage of them skiing their plays in the background. Some of the skiers jump cliffs, some ski freestyle, others ski moguls or powder.
- Park City's America's Opening World Cup special, 1992 November 05; VHS videocassettes (Cassette 144)
  This video contains a fifteen minute special on the America's Opening 1986 World Cup event held at Park City Ski Area which was the first World Cup event hosted in North America. It shows footage of the opening ceremonies held at the University of Utah, highlights from the women's giant slalom event, and the official results and awards ceremony. It also shows clips from the Salt Lake City Ski Ball and the World Cup closing ceremonies.
- America's Opening World Cup: Subaru women's giant slalom, 1992 November 28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 145)
  This video contains ESPN's coverage of the 1992 World Cup Women's Giant Slalom event. It shows highlights from the first run and a full live coverage of the second run. It also contains a skier profile on Diann Roffe and reviews the course and weather conditions.
- America's Opening World Cup: Subaru women's slalom, 1992 November 29; VHS videocassette (Cassette 146)
  This video contains ESPN's coverage of the 1992 World Cup women's slalom event. It shows highlights from the first run and a full live coverage of the second run. It also contains a skier profile on Kristina Koznick and reviews the course and weather conditions.
- America's Opening World Cup: Subaru women's slalom world feed, 1992 November 29; VHS videocassette (Cassette 147)
  This video starts out with a shot of the racecourse from across the valley then shows the women's first and second runs in the slalom event. Throughout these runs, the camera periodically shows the current standings. After the race, there is footage of the awards ceremony and a few replays.
- "Ski The West" promotional summary, 1992 December 05-19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 148)
  "Ski The West" is a series from a television program called Weekend Travel Update. This video compiles several episodes. "Ski The West" shows people how and where to ski in the Western United States, where to stay and what to do with any free time. They feature Park City Ski Area and Deer Valley for their dry, airy powder and their vast terrain, Steamboat, Colorado for their Cowboy downhill race and great terrain, and Squaw Valley for their terrain and surrounding attractions.
- Greg and Sarah Snow's wedding at Park City Ski Area (edited), 1992 December 11; VHS videocassette, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 149-150)
  This video starts out with a view of Parley's Canyon and the surrounding mountains. Then it shows Greg and Sarah skiing together followed by the marriage ceremony which took place on the ski slopes at Park City Ski Area. Next it shows the signing of the marriage license and the newly wed couple says a few words into the camera.
- Subaru Ski World with Bob Beattie, 1992 December 12; VHS videocassette (Cassette 151)
  Subaru Ski World is an ESPN program hosted by Bob Beattie. It contains various skiers' opinions of Park City Ski Area, an interview with Kristen Ulmer, an extreme skier, and a clip of her skiing from "Skiing Extreme V". Bob also interviews members of the U.S. Disabled Ski Team who offer advice to other disabled people who have never skied before. Next they show a clip about Colorado avalanche rescue dogs. Then Bob interviews Jeremy Nobis, a member of the U.S. Ski Team who had just had knee surgery. After this they show clips of horrendous ski racing falls and finally go for a tour of Park City, Utah.
- U.S. Pro Cup Ski Tour: men's slalom, 1992 December 17; VHS videocassette (Cassette 152)
  This video contains ESPN's coverage of the U.S. Pro Cup men's slalom event. It starts with a description of the course from ESPN's course analyzer then shows highlights from the round of thirty-two followed by a full live coverage of the round of sixteen, the quarterfinals, the semifinals and the finals. Throughout the race, ESPN's announcers interview various competitors.
- Park City Ski Area advertisement, 1992 December 10; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 153)
  This video contains an advertisement for Park City Ski Area's 1992 winter season. It advertises the vast terrain that is perfect for skiers of all levels as well as the town of Park City.
- News: Blue Mountain, 1992; VHS videocassette (Cassette 154)
  This video contains a news report on the Jimmy Heuga Ski Express, a fundraiser for disabled skiers. Holly Flanders, who skied for the U.S. Ski Team for four years, helps promote this event along with the help of Park City Ski Area.
- Television news coverage, 1992 September 22-1993 April 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 155)
  9/22/92 KUTV 5 pm "LIVE Weather with Mark Menlove"
  KUTV 6 pm "LIVE Weather"
  11/04 KSL 10 pm "Park City Opens Friday"
  11/06 KSL 6 pm "Pay day run open"
  11/06 KUTV 12 pm "Pay day run open"
  11/06 KUTV 6 pm "Pay day run open"
  11/06 KTVX 5:30 pm "Park City Opens"